# **Fathin Dosunmu**

# FullStack Software Engineer

Address Tallinn, 12611 Harjumaa (Tallinn)

**LinkedIn** https://www.linkedin.com/in/fathindos/

Phone +37253653094

**WWW** https://fathin.vercel.app/

E-mail Fathindos.fd@gmail.com

Web Developer with 3 years of experience in frontend and backend development. Seasoned expert in technologies such as react js, Next Js, firebase, node js, Typescript and Web Security. Experience designing and developing websites from concept to roll out and Passionate about cyber security. Even though I love to get my work done in the best way, I have a great sense of humor.

## **Skills**

Firebase, Google Cloud API	<b>Excellent</b>
React js, Javascript, Typescript, Node JS, Typescript, Next	
HTML5, CSS3, SASS, styled components	Excellent
REST	Excellent
GraphQL	Average
StateManagement: Recoil, Redux	Excellent
CMS: Drupal, Contentful	Good
Git, Confluence	Excellent
Clean Code, Clean Architecture, SOLID principles	
CI/CD, Jenkins, Docker, ArgoCl	Excellent
Can adapt to new tools and frameworks	Excellent
Semantic UI, Material UI	Excellent
Express	Excellent
Docker	Excellent
Linux	Good
Marketing Tools: GA, GTM, Viral Loops	Very Good
Testing: Unit Testing, end to end testing	Very Good
Website Performance	Average  Very Good

## **Work History**

#### 2022-10 - Current

## Front End Software Developer

Monese, Tallinn

- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality and website performance.
- Improved Performance of website on the dev Testing environment
- Mapping out procurement and requirements for Third party integrations such GA, GTM,
   Viral Loops
- Review code of other developers and helped interview candidates
- · And more...

#### 2021-09 - 2022-09

## Developer

Exove, Tallinn

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- · Creating new features for clients with React js, node js, redux, firebase and more
- Checked client code for bugs and weaknesses using approved troubleshooting methods.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers for clients.
- Tested web-based product functionality and delivered iterations to clients.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.

#### 2021-07 - 2021-08

## Frontend Developer Intern

Kuehne+nagel, Tallinn

Key Responsibilities

- Main focus on Redux and its implementations in large scale applications.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling all phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.

#### 2021-02 - 2021-05

#### **Web Developer**

Fundamental Secrets, Florida

Key Responsibilities

- Responsible for developing website product used by approximately 600 + users
- Planned website development, converting ideas into features with HTML, JavaScript, React-is and Firebase
- Implemented payment gateways with Paypal and Stripe.
- Oversaw front-end with mainly React-is and back-end development with mainly firebase.
- Multitasked across multiple functions and ideas to generate project results and meet deadlines.
- Engaged with marketing officer to plan, optimize and repair issues as work environment was changing rapidly.
- Product built and was responsible for: https://fundamentalsecrets.web.app/

#### 2020-06 - 2020-08

### **Test Developer Intern**

Ericsson, Tallinn

Key Responsibilities

- Prepared Software For Testing 5G units before Production.
- Optimized existing code for software Tool within Ericsson's Tech Stack. (C#, SQL and MDX).

• Prepared and Implemented Test criteria and Test Plan in Test Programs for High-Band Products.

## **Education**

2020-09 - Current Master of Science: Cyber Security

Taltech - Tallinn, Estonia

• Https://www.taltech.ee/en/cyber-msc

2017-09 - 2020-06

**Bachelor of Science: Integrated Engineering** 

Taltech - Tallinn, Estonia

• Https://www.taltech.ee/en/integrated-engineering.

## **Hobby Projects**

- Personal Blogpost, where i write about cyber security, hacking and the interesting machine i have hacked on tryhackme: https://medium.com/@fathindos.fd
- Personal Website to showcase my skillset: https://fathin.vercel.app/
- Built a clone of whatsApp Chat. A User can signln, Post a chat in a chat room and chat with other users: https://whatsapp-clone-bd456.web.app/ (React js and Firebase for development)